Mirza Adnan Baig

0755 557 5866 adnanbaig601@gmail.com

Flat 2 Saltwood House, 21 Lovelinch Close, Bermondsey, London, SE15 1HN

PERSONAL STATEMENT

1st/2nd Line IT Support Technician, with almost 6 Years Experience in the IT industry. I left my last role as a field engineer at Excis in august as the travelling to so many different locations wasn't really for me.

I am looking for a 1st and/or 2nd line IT support role in central London where I can commit working in a single office.

I have personal experience with all the main operating systems Windows, Mac OS and Linux all of which I have used for around 10 years though obviously I've been using windows since the 90's. From an IT support perspective however my work has almost exclusively been in the Microsoft ecosystem.

I'm currently using a MacBook as my day to day computer I feel that's where I am weakest from an IT support perspective although I have an old HP with linux and windows 10 dual booted.

EXPERIENCE

IT Field Engineer Excis MSP October 2018 August 2019

Reference: Gabrielle D'arch - gabby@excis.com - +27 81 324 1228

As a field engineer I travelled the country covering for resident engineers annual and sick leave. I was introduced to Skype for Business, SCCM and the SNow (Service Now) ticket management system.

Most of the client companies would use Service Now, and I would always try to resolve tickets straight away obviously trying our best to complete tasks well within SLA's!

Experience (Software):

- * Windows 10
- * Office 365
- * SCCM
- * Skype for Business
- * AD (View only permissions)
- * Service Now ticket management system.

Experience (Hardware):

- * Desktop PC's
- * Laptops
- * Smartphones, Android, iPhone.
- * Printers, HP, Kyocera
- * IP Phones, Cisco, Polycom

1st/2nd Line IT Support Technician, Lookahead 04/2015 - 08-2018

Reference: **John Tilsley** - <u>www.lookahead.org.uk</u> - 0333 010 4600

I was one of three technicians supporting over 1000 users. As a 1st line engineer I was their 1st point of contact when they have any issues with IT systems and technology in general including, windows XP through 10, Android and IOS devices as well as windows tablets. Also, users would occasionally ask for help with using their **personal devices** for remote working, including windows, Mac OS and IOS devices.

Lookahead is a supported housing company with hostels and offices all over the greater London area. I would also go to these external sites to resolve issues that could not be fixed remotely.

Experience (Software):

- * Windows XP, 7, 8, 8.1, 10
- * Android, iOS.
- * Citrix Director, Receiver
- * Heat Call Management (I wouldn't recommend it).
- * App Sense
- * Active Directory, Creating & Managing security and distribution groups, user accounts including very basic tasks like resetting passwords and unlocking accounts.
- * Google Chrome, Google Sheets
- * MS Office 2007, 2010, 365.
- * Exchange Admin centre (before the Office 365 admin centre replaced it).
- * Printer Configuration (logging in via IP)

Experience (Hardware):

- * Thin Clients, (HP, iGel)
- * Desktop PC's
- * Laptops
- * Tablets, iPads, Windows Tablets: Dell, Surface tablets.
- * Smartphones, Android (Motorola, Samsung) iPhone.
- * Routers
- * Switches
- * Printers, HP, Ricoh (Ricoh printers were mostly managed externally).
- * IP Phones, Cisco Polycom

IT (Mobiles) Administrator, Lookahead 11/2013 - 04/2015

I was responsible for administrating all the company's mobile phones initially but as there were only 3 support engineers in the company supporting over 1000 users I ended up helping out and eventually doing first line support as well.

In 2015 we switched mobile provider and my role was deleted. I was then given an official promotion to 1st/2nd line IT support Technician which remained my role until I ended up taking redundancy in 2018.

Experience:

- * Nokias
- * Android
- * Blackberry
- * Windows Phone
- * iPhones
- * iPads

Shop Assistant (PT), Stows Cycles, Slough 04/2010 - 11/2013

Reference: Ian Stow - www.stows.co.uk - 01753 520 528

As a shop assistant in a small family run business, my duties included, cleaning, stocking shelves, serving customers and building bikes for customers and shop displays. Shop assistants were allowed to carry out small repairs such as repairing punctures but services and other repairs would be carried out by a fully trained cycle mechanic.

Apprentice Mechanic, Lays Autos 07/2006 - 09/2006

At the advice of my family I ended up applying for a role in mechanics. I wasn't the best student in school so a high paying academic job was at the time thought to be out of my reach.

Mechanics wasn't really for me and this was visible to my manager at Lays so he decided to let me go.

Shop Assistant (PT), Halfords Slough, 06/2006 - 03/2010

Working as a shop assistant in the Bike section (Bike Hut) my duties included stocking shelves, serving customers either in store or over the phone, building and repairing customers bikes and building bikes for the shop floor. Sometimes when they were short staffed I would have to cover the tills or other departments.

EDUCATION

BTEC LV3 IT, East Berkshire Collage — 2010 - 2012 Pass

BTEC LV2 IT, East Berkshire Collage — 2008 - 2009 Pass

Wexham Secondary School — GCSE's 2006

- * English Language C
- * English Literature D
- * Maths D
- * Science C
- * Electronics B
- * IT D
- * PE C